<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<databaseChangeLog xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
    http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-2.0.xsd">

    <changeSet id="1" author="hhildebrand">
        <sql><![CDATA[
            CREATE TABLE ruleform.coordinate_kind
            (
              id bigserial NOT NULL, -- Otherwise meaningless identifier for a coordinate kind
              name character varying NOT NULL, -- The unique name of a coordinate kind
              description character varying, -- Free-form description of the coordinate kind.
              notes character varying, -- Usage notes for the coordinate kind
              pinned boolean NOT NULL DEFAULT false, -- Indicates whether a coordinate kind rule has been pinned, restricting changes to the rule
              research bigint, -- A research flag that has been set on an individual rule
              updated_by bigint NOT NULL, -- The Resource that last updated this rule
              update_date timestamp with time zone NOT NULL DEFAULT ('now'::text)::timestamp(6) with time zone, -- The time at which this rule was last updated
              nestable boolean NOT NULL DEFAULT false, -- Indicates whether this CoordinateKind can be repeatedly nested within coordinates of the same kind.
              CONSTRAINT coordinate_kind_pkey PRIMARY KEY (id ),
              CONSTRAINT coordinate_kind_research_fkey FOREIGN KEY (research)
                  REFERENCES ruleform.research (id) MATCH SIMPLE
                  ON UPDATE CASCADE ON DELETE NO ACTION DEFERRABLE INITIALLY IMMEDIATE,
              CONSTRAINT coordinate_kind_updated_by_fkey FOREIGN KEY (updated_by)
                  REFERENCES ruleform.resource (id) MATCH SIMPLE
                  ON UPDATE CASCADE ON DELETE NO ACTION DEFERRABLE INITIALLY IMMEDIATE
            )
            WITH (
              OIDS=FALSE
            );
            COMMENT ON TABLE ruleform.coordinate_kind
                IS 'The various kinds of coordinates that are defined in the system.  Each kind of coordinate has a characteristic internal structure.';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.id 
                IS 'Otherwise meaningless identifier for a coordinate kind';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.name 
                IS 'The unique name of a coordinate kind';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.description 
                IS 'Free-form description of the coordinate kind.';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.notes IS 
                'Usage notes for the coordinate kind';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.pinned IS 
                'Indicates whether a coordinate kind rule has been pinned, restricting changes to the rule';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.research IS 
                'A research flag that has been set on an individual rule';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.updated_by 
                IS 'The Resource that last updated this rule';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.update_date 
                IS 'The time at which this rule was last updated';
            COMMENT ON COLUMN ruleform.coordinate_kind.nestable 
                IS 'Indicates whether this CoordinateKind can be repeatedly nested within coordinates of the same kind.';
            ]]>
        </sql>
        <rollback>
            <dropTable tableName="ruleform.coordinate_kind"/>
        </rollback>
    </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>
